A Guide to the Minutes of the Virginia Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission, 1974-2005
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Minutes of the Virginia Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission, 1974-2005
The Library of Virginia
51800
35 cu. ft. (35 boxes)
Virginia. General Assembly. Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred on 13 May 2016 from JLARC, 201 N. 9th St., General Assembly Building, 11th floor, Richmond, Va. 23219.
Biographical Information
The Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission (JLARC) is responsible for legislative oversight and government accountability. The Commission studies and makes recommendations regarding program and agency savings, helps to improve agency efficiency and effectiveness, works to maintain an informed citizenry and legislature, and oversees agency compliance with legislative intent. The work of the Commission ensures that funds appropriated by the Virginia General Assembly are used effectively and efficiently by State and local agencies.
The Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission was created in 1973 and became operational in early 1974. The Commission is composed of nine members of the House of Delegates and five members of the Senate. At least five of the Delegates also serve on the House Appropriations Committee, and two of the Senators also serve on the Senate Finance Committee. Delegates are appointed by the Speaker of the House, and Senators by the Senate Rules Committee. The Chair is elected by a majority of Commission members and usually rotates every two years between the House and Senate. The Auditor of Public Accounts is a nonvoting, ex officio member. The Commission has a full-time staff led by a Director who is appointed by the Commission and confirmed by the General Assembly for a six-year term of office.
A fundamental change in evaluation authority occurred in 1977 with enactment of the Legislative Program Review and Evaluation Act. This act provided for a more systematic process of legislative oversight through a better defined topic selection process and direct involvement of General Assembly standing committees. (The JLARC authority is outlined in Title 30, Chapters 7 and 8 of the Code of Virginia).
Scope and Content
Minutes and related attachments, 1974-2005, documenting the meetings, activities, discussions, policy decisions and recommendations of the Virginia Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission [JLARC]. Includes minutes, as well as agendas, correspondence, reports, studies and work plans.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Minutes, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
- Minutes, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
- Minutes, 1978 (Box 3)
- Minutes, 1979 (Box 4)
- Minutes, 1980 January-August (Box 5)
- Minutes, 1980 September-December (Box 6)
- Minutes, 1981 January-March (Box 7)
- Minutes, 1981 April-December (Box 8)
- Minutes, 1982 January-May (Box 9)
- Minutes, 1982 June-December (Box 10)
- Minutes, 1983 January-April (Box 11)
- Minutes, 1983 May-December (Box 12)
- Minutes, 1984 (Box 13)
- Minutes, 1985 January-May (Box 14)
- Minutes, 1985 May-December (Box 15)
- Minutes, 1986 (Box 16)
- Minutes, 1987 (Box 17)
- Minutes, 1988 (Box 18)
- Minutes, 1989 (Box 19)
- Minutes, 1990 (Box 20)
- Minutes, 1991 (Box 21)
- Minutes, 1992 (Box 22)
- Minutes, 1993 (Box 23)
- Minutes, 1994 (Box 24)
- Minutes, 1995 (Box 25)
- Minutes, 1996 (Box 26)
- Minutes, 1997 (Box 27)
- Minutes, 1998 (Box 28)
- Minutes, 1999 (Box 29)
- Minutes, 2000 (Box 30)
- Minutes, 2001 (Box 31)
- Minutes, 2002 (Box 32)
- Minutes, 2003 (Box 33)
- Minutes, 2004 (Box 34)
- Minutes, 2005 (Box 35)